Dalton Valliere

842 Davis St, Apt 4 Kalamazoo, MI 49008 edvallie@gmail.com 248-787-0771

Summary

I am a full stack developer with over 5 years of professional experience. My experience covers the entire life cycle of the software development process. I have worked on many web applications from the design phase, through development, and into an administration and maintenance stage.

Professional Experience

Title-Check LLC, Kalamazoo MI

Position: Web Developer

March 2013 - Current

- Re-wrote primary customer facing website from scratch in Symfony2
- Object-Oriented PHP web development and document generation
- Designed and developed in-house escrow management system
- Migrated primary web and hosting servers into a KVM based virtualized environment
- Developed in-house document retrieval API

Kaufman Financial Group, Farmington Hills MI

Position: Helpdesk Technician

January 2012 – March 2013

- Created and managed MDT imaging process
- Supported more than 1,000 users in Citrix environment
- Created a solution to move old e-mail archives from a third party system into the current Symantec Vault system

Western Michigan University - CS Department, Kalamazoo MI

Position: Systems Administrator

December 2006 – September 2008, September 2010 – May 2011

- Provided programming support for CS students
- Used Bash scripting to automate backup and logging processes
- Managed MSDN software distribution for Computer Science faculty and students
- Hosted and maintained distribution mirrors for Ubuntu, MSDN, Gentoo, Knoppix, Sabayon, Cygwin, CentOS and Blastwave

Kellogg Company, Battle Creek MI

Position: IT Intern – CRM Team

June 2009 – September 2010

- Development inside a customized SAP CRM Module with ABAP
- Oracle database management with TOAD
- Responsible for development of Access DuPage website, part of a community intern project
- Participated in testing systems for Program GO!, a full-scale implementation of the SAP HR module
- Project manager for the 2010 Kelloggs summer IT internship project

Western Michigan University – EUP, Kalamazoo MI

Position: LAN Specialist

August 2008 - June 2009

- Supported Western Michigan University faculty with laptop swap-out initiative
- Deployed and maintained Debian based development and production level servers

Education

Western Michigan University, Haworth College of Business

Major: Computer Information Systems

Minor: General Business

Volunteer & Other Activities

- President, Computer Club at Western Michigan University
- Founder and team leader of the Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition Team at Western Michigan University
- Kalamazoo Area Runners member
- CCNA Networking Courses
- Volunteered at Friendship Village Retirement Community teaching computer skills
- Business Technology Network at Western Michigan University member
- Managed and organized over ten large LAN parties on behalf of the Computer Club with attendance peaking over 100 people

Technical Skills

- PHP web development and scripting
- MVC web application development with Symfony and Symfony2
- Git version control
- HTML5, Javascript(jQuery), Bootstrap, Twig and CSS3 website markup
- RESTful API development
- C# and VB.NET development in classroom and workplace settings
- Database Design
- Documentation of Servers, Special Software Procedures, Surplus and Maintenance Logs
- Shell Scripting in Bash, Ksh and Perl
- Windows Powershell
- ABAP Development within the SAP TPM Module
- PostgreSQL, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Servers 2005 and 2008
- Apache and NGINX management
- Virtualization with KVM and OpenVZ
- BIND DNS management
- Experience with LDAP and Kerberos
- Active Directory User and Device Management
- General network maintenance and administration(DHCP, DNS, Routing, etc)
- Network monitoring with Wireshark and Tcpdump
- Zabbix server monitoring
- Elastix PBX management
- Gitlab setup and administration
- Mediawiki installation and process documentation
- Ubuntu, Debian, Red Hat and CentOS, FreeBSD, HP-UX, Solaris and Windows